[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cb", "question": "What day did the Battle of the Somme begin?", "answer": "July 1, 1916", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc3906ce05a3942286f24", "question": "Lindsey Buckingham is the lead guitarist for what British-American band?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c337", "question": "Which grow faster - fingernails or toenails?", "answer": "Fingernails", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ae8637d7f28483af1e7fdca", "question": "What country would you find Mount Elbrus in?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51a0aff04d658268c9304", "question": "Which American revolutionary figure was a philosopher?", "answer": "Thomas Paine, the patriot who penned the philosophical treatise \"The Rights of Man\" and the revolutionary pamphlet \"Common Sense\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a6", "question": "What does Montana's motto \"oro y plata\" mean in English?", "answer": "Gold and silver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c478", "question": "What does the acronym SETI stand for in \"SETI Institute\"?", "answer": "Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ef", "question": "Who was appointed the first leader of the Tuskegee Institute in 1881?", "answer": "Booker T. Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2146c31a458464a93c456", "question": "When was the last time Easter Sunday and April Fool's Day occurred on the same day in the 20th century?", "answer": "1956", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a191", "question": "Who released an album in 1973 titled \"Goodbye Yellow Brick Road?\"", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a24c9d816e292245c14", "question": "Who painted \"The Persistence of Memory\"?", "answer": "Salvador Dal\u00ed -- \"The Persistence of Memory,\" aka \"The Melting Watches,\" is one of Dali's most recognizable works.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008e89cf842fa4c4ba96b3", "question": "On what sea did the \"Battle of Jutland\" take place?", "answer": "North Sea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25835b63e5727cf5a4846", "question": "What was actually the \u201cweb\u201d in the first Spider-man wrist web-shooter toy introduced in the 1970s?", "answer": "String", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f3", "question": "What is the lowest hand that beats a straight in Poker?", "answer": "A flush", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb1beeff497e33de8057919", "question": "How many points did LeBron James score in his very first NBA game?", "answer": "25", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1f", "question": "A nilometer measures the level of what?", "answer": "The river Nile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c290", "question": "What is the term for an organism that lives on or in another?", "answer": "Parasite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59db75270ab2c8f322317fe5", "question": "Peridot is which month's birthstone?", "answer": "August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde4a62c6c6b019850c9a74", "question": "What was the warship that exploded in Havana Harbor, precipitating the Spanish-American War?", "answer": "USS Maine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ca", "question": "Who created the operating system \"Linux\"?", "answer": "Linus Torvalds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4c", "question": "The character Uriah Heep appeared in which Charles Dickens novel?", "answer": "David Copperfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a88", "question": "What is Principal Skinner\u2019s mother\u2019s name on the TV show \"The Simpson's\"?", "answer": "Agnes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007849bbd51d85e222ab65c", "question": "What was the first fruit that was eaten on the moon?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfca", "question": "American Hamilton Smith patented what in 1858?", "answer": "A washing machine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23c", "question": "What royal subject married Marie Antoinette?", "answer": "Louis XVI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a0", "question": "What movie starred Johnny Depp as Willy Wonka?", "answer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c57b", "question": "What is the common name for \"alopecia\"?", "answer": "Baldness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd18c3129d03ab85b632b33", "question": "Who first said, \"Genius is one percent inspiration, ninety-nine percent perspiration\"?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388de", "question": "Who competed against Athena to be the patron god of Athens?", "answer": "Poseidon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a498", "question": "Into which sea does the Nile river flow?", "answer": "The Mediterranean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a433", "question": "What is the capital of Spain?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338def", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"pal\"?", "answer": "Romany", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d8", "question": "What movie stopped production for a year so Tom Hanks can grow out his hair and lose 50 pounds?", "answer": "Cast Away", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa9", "question": "Which author wrote \"The Wild Palms\"?", "answer": "William Faulkner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523e9a736d4be723796b51", "question": "What is Toronto\u2019s Pearson International Airport code?", "answer": "YYZ", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a622a2ebb971c1417fb8c", "question": "Which French district does Claret come from?", "answer": "Bordeaux", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c822fbde8045e48466d0", "question": "A medical condition that has been caused by a physician or medical treatment is described as what?", "answer": "Latrogenic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e97", "question": "What movie did the villain Noah Cross appear in?", "answer": "Chinatown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963c", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Prince Philip?", "answer": "Princess Aurora's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b0", "question": "What female spy was arrested and sentenced to death in France in 1917 for spying on behalf of the Germans?", "answer": "Mata Hari", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fe", "question": "What kind of poisoning is known as plumbism?", "answer": "Lead poisoning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c8f", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was warned that the cow was in the corn?", "answer": "Little Boy Blue", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab79", "question": "What large African island nation is located just west of Mauritius?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a172", "question": "What was the first film Paul Newman directed?", "answer": "Rachel, Rachel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe938766bd93ce3a4e5f685", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 2009 for studies of the structure and function of the ribosome?", "answer": "Ada E. Yonath", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af54", "question": "In which battle was Nelson killed?", "answer": "Battle of Trafalgar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a4", "question": "For what movie did Humphrey Bogart win his only Oscar?", "answer": "The African Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e09", "question": "What New York banker did Star Jones marry in 2004?", "answer": "Al Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c07", "question": "What was Anna Nicole Smith's full birth name?", "answer": "Vickie Lynn Hogan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18f", "question": "What was the name of Barney and Betty Rubble\u2019s adopted son in \"The Flintstones\"?", "answer": "Bamm-Bamm Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c32", "question": "How many seasons did the TV show \"Twin Peaks\" run for?", "answer": "2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339540", "question": "What show is \"The end of something simple. And the beginning of everything else\"?", "answer": "Dawson's Creek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c325", "question": "What does the acronym RPM stand for?", "answer": "Revolutions per minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008e011f4f3bc4a292f862e", "question": "In old world Europe, which holiday used to be celebrated on April 1?", "answer": "New Year's Day -- Pope Gregory XIII ordered the implementation of the Gregorian Calendar in 1582, which changed it to January 1.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b57197867df192a942e3363", "question": "Who directed the 1946 film \"It's a Wonderful Life\"?", "answer": "Frank Capra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c957", "question": "Approximately how many miles is an Astronomical Unit?", "answer": "93 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ec", "question": "What fish became popular at fish stores after the release of \"Finding Nemo\"?", "answer": "Clown fish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5afad78e430e050a5df0d10f", "question": "H.J. Heinz Company is based in which American City?", "answer": "Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae860f34007905755f79e90", "question": "Who was the first woman in space?", "answer": "Valentina Tereshkova", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc1", "question": "What band's Greatest Hits album set a US record by going 29 times platinum?", "answer": "Eagles'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba659874c93a3298b2158", "question": "What is the nickname given to Negan's bat in the TV show \"The Walking Dead\"?", "answer": "Lucille", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c9be0775fa611bce67ef", "question": "McDonald\u2019s restaurant periodically runs a themed promotion based on what board game?", "answer": "Monopoly -- Since 1987, McDonald's customers have been hoping to win prizes using game pieces off their soda cups and fries.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bced", "question": "Who chose her new name in 1953 to honor a Danish surgeon named Christian Hamburger?", "answer": "Christine Jorgensen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea783dff048f679a45abd6", "question": "What process produces a duplicate of the original cell?", "answer": "Mitosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be22", "question": "In what country was actor Rick Fox born?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071c4b3745b36be73039ca", "question": "What is the name of the infamous chicken fighter that appears throughout the \"Chew\" comics series?", "answer": "Poyo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fc856c1abc30a8194e188b3", "question": "Who was piloting the Enola Gay when it dropped the atomic bomb on Hiroshima?", "answer": "The bombardier, Tom Ferebee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a927", "question": "Where is the Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Springfield, Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8c", "question": "Which \"Batman\" movie co-starred Nicole Kidman as Dr. Chase Meridian?", "answer": "Batman Forever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d119ee4fea7fe947a22292", "question": "On the Fahrenheit scale, there are 180 degrees between which two important points?", "answer": "Freezing and boiling points", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b228", "question": "What city was Elizabeth Short killed in?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c079", "question": "What is the fear of knees known as?", "answer": "Genuphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef65b56ce05a3942286e70", "question": "Who is the Winslow family\u2019s nerdy neighbor in \"Family Matters\"", "answer": "Steve Urkel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c91f877e98cb977789ef", "question": "In which U.S. city can you ride the Mud Island Monorail?", "answer": "Memphis, Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a426", "question": "In which country would you find St. Basil's cathedral?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac4", "question": "What is the name for the number 1 followed by 100 zeros?", "answer": "Googol", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baca", "question": "On a medical diploma, what does D.D.S. stand for?", "answer": "Doctor of Dental Surgery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339665", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is Springfield Elementary's music teacher?", "answer": "Mr. Largo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c873877e98cb977789e5", "question": "Where can you visit a museum devoted to failed inventions?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d96", "question": "Who replaced Stanley Kubrick on the western film \"One-Eyed Jacks\", making it the only film he ever directed?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b7", "question": "Who played the role of Ricky Stratton on the TV show \"Silver Spoons\"?", "answer": "Ricky Schroeder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4a7e49076251badbeab7", "question": "What was former US President William Taft\u2019s pet cow named?", "answer": "Pauline", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a803", "question": "What city is overlooked by a large statue named \"Christ the Redeemer\"?", "answer": "Rio de Janeiro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c692", "question": "A nebula is a large interstellar cloud of what?", "answer": "Dust and gases", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d3", "question": "On what holiday did Harry Houdini die in 1926?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd7", "question": "In episode of \"Seinfeld\", what popular candy did Jerry become addicted to?", "answer": "Pez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007823abd51d85e222ab655", "question": "How did the Mus\u00e9e Picasso in Paris come to own its collection of Picasso's works?", "answer": "Since he left no will, his\u00a0death duties\u00a0to the French state were paid in the form of works from his personal collection.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899c4760d398dc9cf7a6a7", "question": "Hestia is the daughter of which two titans?", "answer": "Cronus and Rhea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe1ec09145fb29466707384", "question": "In which country is Stilton cheese produced?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600243ad4be4723ccac22199", "question": "Which American author wrote the novel \"The Color Purple\"?", "answer": "Alice Walker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febbcc97e83c707845b2151", "question": "Popular actress Gabrielle Union married which NBA player in 2014?", "answer": "Dwayne Wade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a029", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", who did Peter force to become a professional boxer?", "answer": "Lois", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77d", "question": "What precious stones were originally used to polish axes in the Stone Age?", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcba", "question": "What model was married to musician Seal?", "answer": "Heidi Klum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe698bb20565ad31a57c738", "question": "Who kept Odysseus trapped on a remote island for seven years.", "answer": "Calypso", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010ca2e0775fa611bce67f4", "question": "Which famed beauty company was named in part for its founder's sister?", "answer": "Maybelline -- Thomas Lyle Williams developed a product for darkening eyebrows and eyelashes and named it after his sister Mabel.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98b", "question": "What is added to Gin to make Pink Gin?", "answer": "Angostura Bitters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad9", "question": "What was the common archaic name for a giraffe?", "answer": "Camelopard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b788", "question": "What style of pants is named after an island in the Gulf of Naples?", "answer": "Capri pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8ffa401dd7bf43be5e863", "question": "Who said, \"It does not matter how slowly you go as long as you do not stop.\"?", "answer": "Confucius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e7", "question": "What \"imaginary\" number is defined as the square root of -1?", "answer": "i", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339079", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Turandot\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339313", "question": "What did the license plate read on the team's response vehicle in the movie \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Ecto-1", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36b", "question": "What country administers Greenland?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60136f6c1381754895396376", "question": "Where is Superman\u2019s Fortress of Solitude?", "answer": "Arctic Circle -- Although he's had different bachelor pads, he classically heads to the Arctic Circle when he wants to be alone.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f4d44af848b908361b880", "question": "What year was the first color photograph taken?", "answer": "1861", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e986bebfabb9c85d8a96b", "question": "Who released the album \"Tuesday Night Music Club\" in 1993?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a63ef2ebb971c1417fb9f", "question": "Which famous classical composer's music was featured in the film \"Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "Beethoven's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02d", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Stewie took captive the cast of which hit TV show?", "answer": "Star Trek: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b745", "question": "What Biblical name literally means \"the sunny one\"?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b740", "question": "Who is widely credited as being the inventor of the modern commercially available toilet paper?", "answer": "Joseph Gayetty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899b4160d398dc9cf7a69b", "question": "Egg Fu is the enemy of what superhero?", "answer": "Wonder Woman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b3589e25db0d66a186cb54f", "question": "French fries are claimed to have originated in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339533", "question": "Who was Larry Sanders' sidekick on \"The Larry Sanders Show\"?", "answer": "Hank Kingsley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a914", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Leavenworth?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d8", "question": "In the computer world, does the abbreviation DOS stand for?", "answer": "Disk Operating System", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a683", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Treasure State\"?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9a", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Sawyer?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5aab2e6958d116dab4aecb3e", "question": "Inanna is the ancient Sumerian goddess of what?", "answer": "Love, fertility and war", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93bce6bd93ce3a4e5f6a6", "question": "Percentage-wise, how big were the brains of the extinct species Australopithecus compared to a modern human brain?", "answer": "35%", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ee", "question": "Which TV mom is a member of the \"Galaxy Women Historical Society\"?", "answer": "Jane Jetson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f4", "question": "What chess piece has a horse's head?", "answer": "Knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c48c", "question": "What garden flower's name literally means \"nose twister\"?", "answer": "Nasturtium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce4", "question": "Which \"Friends\" character is the answer to the trivia question in the SNL \"Lazy Sunday\" sketch?", "answer": "Matthew Perry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b678", "question": "A \"top-sider\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9096c01dd7bf43be5e88f", "question": "Aphyllous trees lack what?", "answer": "Leaves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac79", "question": "During which American period did stock car racing gain most of its popularity?", "answer": "The Prohibition", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399dc", "question": "On what TV show did Nell Carter work as a housekeeper for the Kanisky family?", "answer": "Gimme a Break!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a118", "question": "On the 80's album \"Purple Rain\", who backed Prince?", "answer": "The Revolution", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8480ec223966ae8f87ff", "question": "Which mixed drink was made famous by rapper Snoop Doggy Dogg in the 1990's?", "answer": "Gin and Juice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062bfac9d816e292245c27", "question": "What artist is best known for a painting of his mother?", "answer": "James McNeil Whistler's most famous painting is \"Arrangement in Black and Grey No.1\".  It is commonly known \"Whistler's Mother\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a53b", "question": "What US city is nicknamed the \"Motor City\"?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892a", "question": "In Larry Niven's novel \"Ringworld\", what is the drug that extends human life to near immortality?", "answer": "Boosterspice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a978", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Riksdag?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d27", "question": "What children's books character is scared of Heffalumps and Woozles?", "answer": "Winnie the Pooh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b323343bf195a31e15d739a", "question": "Gaborone is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffc5e1cf6db9ac4808cfd", "question": "What U.S. city's airport code is MCO?", "answer": "Orlando, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef92e66ce05a3942286e88", "question": "Who is the first mainstream artist known for utilizing the infamous Auto-Tune vocal distortion technique?", "answer": "Cher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe259a9658e585fda9cfa42", "question": "What car feature did Ralph Teetor invent despite being blind?", "answer": "Cruise control", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c88e5da22f44c2d77a29c3e", "question": "What narrow strip of water connects the Atlantic Ocean to the Mediterranean Sea?", "answer": "The Strait of Gibraltar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1e", "question": "The last two surviving jurors from the film \"12 Angry Men\" were actors who shared what first name?", "answer": "Jack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf4", "question": "How many Grammy Awards did Frank Sinatra receive during his career?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993e", "question": "Which Spice Girl married to soccer star David Beckham in 1999?", "answer": "Posh Spice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aca", "question": "On what TV show did the characters often hang out at the Warsaw Tavern?", "answer": "The Drew Carey Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a282", "question": "Who directed the 1989 film \"The War of the Roses\"?", "answer": "Danny DeVito", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef0", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Willy Loman?", "answer": "Death of a Salesman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e1", "question": "Calamarata pasta is shaped like what?", "answer": "Wide rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067b19ff9c0647b50a8060", "question": "The Gotthard Base Tunnel, which opened on June 1, 2016, is located in which country?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b28f", "question": "How many amendments have been made to the US Constitution?", "answer": "27", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf5", "question": "What year was actress Julia Roberts born?", "answer": "1967", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007815fbd51d85e222ab64b", "question": "What art movement employs aspects of mass culture, such as advertising, comic books and mundane cultural objects?", "answer": "Seeking to elevate popular culture to the level of fine art,\u00a0Pop artists\u00a0celebrated commonplace objects and everyday people.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b62c", "question": "A \"black and tan\" is a mixture of Bass Ale and what other beer?", "answer": "Guinness Stout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338894", "question": "What did Rumpelstiltskin spin into gold?", "answer": "Straw", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa4f", "question": "In which African country would you find the towns of Kumasi and Cape?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a330", "question": "What year did Belle and Sebastian originally release the album \"Tigermilk\"?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbe696ce05a3942286eef", "question": "Who recorded the song, \"I Heard a Rumour\"?", "answer": "Bananarama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fed2bbaec223966ae8f8911", "question": "What is the name of the smelly green ghost in \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Slimer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eaea6f83302ff91e4648b", "question": "In TV, what does SCTV stand for?", "answer": "Second City Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b4", "question": "What movie features singing siblings named Liesl, Friedrich, Brigitta, Louisa, Kurt, Marta and Gretl?", "answer": "The Sound of Music", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97d", "question": "What constellation is Polaris located in?", "answer": "Ursa Minor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071cfb3745b36be73039d2", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the V-2 rocket for Nazi Germany and later the Saturn V rocket for the United States?", "answer": "Wernher von Braun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f8", "question": "What Olympic field event's two main styles are the glide and the spin?", "answer": "Shot put's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062d1ac9d816e292245c31", "question": "What landmark work came about from a friend's request for a self-portrait of Rene Magritte?", "answer": "\"The Son of Man\"\u00a0(A friend's request for a self-portrait of Rene Magritte, which was a man's face obscured by a piece of fruit.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cce", "question": "What civil rights anthem is actually a rewrite of the hymn \"Keep Your Hands on the Plow, Hold On\"?", "answer": "Keep Your Eyes on the Prize", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bd", "question": "What part of the eye changes shape in LASIK surgery?", "answer": "The cornea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909cf4fbb53d1af658864f3", "question": "Which African country was released from British and French oversight on Christmas Eve, 1951?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a1", "question": "What traditionally tops the meat in a shepherd's pie?", "answer": "Mashed potatoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac21", "question": "The Republic of Suriname is part of which continent?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937eb5b08d98002fdd633ad", "question": "Which three family members released an album titled \"Priority\" in 1979?", "answer": "The Pointer Sisters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3fbec73aa70ea0b70b03", "question": "For the film \"The Empire Strikes Back,\" where were scenes set on the ice planet Hoth actually filmed?", "answer": "The Battle of Hoth scenes were shot on Handangerjokulen Glacier near the village of Finse, Norway.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931f", "question": "In the movie \"Flashdance\", what was Alex Owen's day job?", "answer": "Steel worker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59068295ff9c0647b50a809e", "question": "On what streaming platform was Kanye West\u2019s \"The Life of Pablo\" album launched?", "answer": "Tidal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fee", "question": "Who got his signature left-ear piercing in 1986, after interviewee Liza Minnelli encouraged him to do it?", "answer": "Ed Bradley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c553", "question": "What is studied by nephrology?", "answer": "Kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f8", "question": "What is the name of the Volkswagen in Disney\u2019s \"The Love Bug\"?", "answer": "Herbie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf5", "question": "The candy PEZ was first sold in which country?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc1226ce05a3942286f0f", "question": "In the film \"The Bourne Ultimatum,\" where is the \"Treadstone\" facility located?", "answer": "415 East 71st Street, NYC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05d", "question": "Which constitutional amendment gives US citizens the right to bear arms?", "answer": "Second", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339368", "question": "In the 1960 movie \"Psycho\", what actor plays the private detective?", "answer": "Martin Balsam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007820ebd51d85e222ab652", "question": "What object commonly appears in Picasso's paintings?", "answer": "Guitars (Although his Cubist works approach abstraction, he never relinquished the objects of the real world as subject matter.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4b58a06d333868d34d6e9", "question": "In the U.S., what famous slogan first appeared on World War I recruiting posters?", "answer": "\"I want you\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a5", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named for the father of Pelops?", "answer": "Tantalum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba51", "question": "What was the denomination of the first American adhesive stamp?", "answer": "Five cents", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e06", "question": "What comic strip introduced the metal band Billy and the Boingers?", "answer": "Bloom County", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b6", "question": "How many sides does a trapezoid have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca9", "question": "In what century did Leonardo Da Vinci paint the \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "16th Century", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ea0b06d333868d34d759", "question": "After the bombing of Pearl Harbor which brand of potato chips changed its name to Jays?", "answer": "Japps potato chips", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc1e76de0eb824d4052e3", "question": "What islands make up the British Virgin Islands?", "answer": "The British Virgin Islands is a former colony that includes the islands of Virgin Gorda, Tortola, Anegada, and Jost Van Dyke.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbdf", "question": "What is the last name of the founder of the Papa John's pizza chain?", "answer": "Schnatter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5989a8abcb8751d53e7d75fd", "question": "Who won Super Bowl IV?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d0", "question": "Which US president on Mount Rushmore has a mustache?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b315", "question": "What was created almost 7,000 years ago by the eruption of Mount Mazama?", "answer": "Crater Lake", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339697", "question": "What TV family lived at Southfork Ranch?", "answer": "The Ewings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c93", "question": "How does Juliet die in Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "She stabs herself", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a8", "question": "What U.S. state gave the world Little Richard, Otis Redding and Gladys Knight?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a61", "question": "What disco queen's first gold record was 1975's \"Love to Love You Baby\"?", "answer": "Donna Summer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e1b6e748bb36357acdf6", "question": "Who is the singer behind the albums \"1989\" and \"Reputation\"?", "answer": "Taylor Swift", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fcf3a4edfd43a087adc6", "question": "What number is represented by \"D\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f95b05555722f97b22684dc", "question": "Who was the Hogwarts' headmaster right before Dumbledore?", "answer": "Armando Dippet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c789", "question": "The Earth's ozone layer absorbs what type of radiation from the Sun?", "answer": "Ultraviolet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f34dff048f679a45aabe", "question": "What inorganic molecule does lightning produce?", "answer": "Ozone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e3", "question": "What was the middle name of composer Bach?", "answer": "Sebastian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba85", "question": "Who succeeded Tom Brokaw as anchor on NBC\u2019s Nightly News in 2004?", "answer": "Brian Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0a", "question": "In Greek myth, what nine sisters are the daughters of Mnemosyne?", "answer": "The Muses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c78", "question": "Which movie introduced Indiana Jones to the public?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdac8e347d002c297e4d7", "question": "What instrument did Yehudi Menuhin play?", "answer": "The violin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfe", "question": "In which movie did Kim Novak portray a witch?", "answer": "Bell, Book and Candle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fbfea4edfd43a087adbe", "question": "What is the symbol of the Zodiac sign Leo?", "answer": "The Lion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c684", "question": "What sense would you not have if you were anosmic?", "answer": "Smell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ba", "question": "Who famously said \"When in doubt tell the truth.\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec877fec223966ae8f8815", "question": "Which rock legend's real name is William Bailey?", "answer": "Axl Rose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ff", "question": "Who was Stan Laurel's partner?", "answer": "Oliver Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7b", "question": "Who has been called the first victim of the \"Madden curse\" due to his abrupt 1999 retirement?", "answer": "Barry Sanders", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0cb", "question": "Whose debut solo album was entitled \"Schizophonic\"?", "answer": "Geri Halliwell's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996e", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Principal Skinner's mother?", "answer": "Agnes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15b", "question": "What popular figure was born Agnese Gonxhe Bojaxhiu?", "answer": "Mother Teresa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62f", "question": "What is the two letter postal abbreviation for Massachusetts?", "answer": "MA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4d9a4e08b8581f80b092bb", "question": "Which month saw the release of the film \"Star Wars: The Last Jedi\"?", "answer": "December", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ea6508d98002fdd633a2", "question": "What is the largest body of fresh water by volume?", "answer": "Lake Baikal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c7ae0775fa611bce67dc", "question": "What does ABV stand for in the beer industry?", "answer": "Alcohol By Volume", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8945ec223966ae8f8827", "question": "The tagline \"Justice has its price\" comes from which 1998 movie?", "answer": "\"A Civil Action\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901d90d709c1c34536e6eaa", "question": "In what year did the Ultimate Fighting Championship start?", "answer": "1993", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba5", "question": "What novel, written by E.B. White, tells the story of an adopted mouse?", "answer": "Stuart Little", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339375", "question": "In the movie \"Cast Away\", how long was Chuck Nolan marooned on the island?", "answer": "4 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee6", "question": "What two colors make the color green?", "answer": "Blue and yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3af", "question": "Which British designer invented the Dual Cyclone bagless vacuum cleaner?", "answer": "James Dyson", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a1", "question": "What is the largest of the islands off the southern coast of Cape Cod?", "answer": "Martha's Vineyard", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d86", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Manhunter\" based on?", "answer": "Red Dragon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c8", "question": "The singer Shakira comes from what country?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b6", "question": "The TV mini-series \"Rich Man, Poor Man\" was based on the lives of what family?", "answer": "The Jordache Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e02ee748bb36357acdec", "question": "The cities of Xai-Xai, Panda, and Beira are in what country?", "answer": "Mozambique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa7", "question": "Angostura Bitters were first sold in what year?", "answer": "1824", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a83", "question": "What Biblical figure's wife was turned into a pillar of salt?", "answer": "Lot's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afe", "question": "What 1995 Kevin Costner film was the most expensive movie ever made, until \"Titanic\" came along in 1997?", "answer": "Waterworld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de1", "question": "Who was married to her radio comedy partner Phil Harris from 1941 to 1995?", "answer": "Alice Faye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64e", "question": "What must a mole do every four hours so it doesn't die?", "answer": "Eat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc3d8ec223966ae8f8881", "question": "Where does Brooks in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\" work after he got out of prison?", "answer": "A grocery store", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a9", "question": "What US city is nicknamed \"The Big Peach\"?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d1", "question": "The Roanoke Colony was established in which present-day US State?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b6", "question": "Which movie popularized the phrase \"You had me at hello.\"?", "answer": "Jerry Maguire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc34cec223966ae8f887d", "question": "Tiger Woods set or tied 27 records at which 1997 PGA tournament?", "answer": "The Masters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ca", "question": "What year was the movie \"Aliens\" released?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e8a67c89a45431f553a9cd2", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad30", "question": "What US president endorsed the Louisiana Purchase in 1803?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3b7", "question": "Which ocean is the world's largest ocean?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597ddf0577980686f722d181", "question": "What year was the first official soccer game played?", "answer": "1863", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ce", "question": "In what city was the Fresh Prince of Bel-Air born and raised?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd4", "question": "In 1991, who erected three thousand blue and yellow umbrellas on the coasts of California and Japan?", "answer": "Christo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b2", "question": "Which movie was Pixar's first feature film?", "answer": "Toy Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee1", "question": "Whom did James Earl Ray assassinate?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ae", "question": "Who was the first African-American to win an Academy Award for an acting role?", "answer": "Hattie McDaniel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbd", "question": "What model was married to musician Travis Barker?", "answer": "Shanna Moakler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06d", "question": "What artist had the first rap album to ever go to No. 1 on the US pop charts?", "answer": "MC Hammer", "category": "entertainment"}]